Christopher James Smith - Senior Software Engineer

csmith4work@gmail.com

Professional Summary

I am a passionate software engineer with over 5 years of experience working in every capacity of the software development lifecycle. Specializing in Full Stack Development, I've gathered requirements, architected solutions, implemented code, curated tests and managed the release and updates of various products and tools. I've learned that I excel in working on the forefront of technology, providing my skills to help create new solutions and integrations where none existed before. I value gathering all of the relevant context and requirements for a project, consistent communication, managing expectations and proper documentation and project management. This ensures that my software delivery can be as robust as possible while also maintaining efficiency during the development process.

Core Skills

Area	Skills and Competencies
Application and Web Development	C# and Dotnet, Python, Node.JS, Vue and Nuxt.JS, React.JS,
	Typescript, GraphQL, JQuery, SASS
Cloud Infrastructure	AWS, Terraform, IAM
Compute Infrastructure and Tooling	EC2, Docker, ECR, ECS, Lambda,
	Kubernetes, Helm, Heroku
Software Integration	SNS, SQS, Stripe, RioSEO, Airtable,
	Contentful, FFMPEG, Google API,
	Infor
Data Storage	S3, SQL Server, MongoDB,
-	Postgres, RDS, DynamoDb
Automation (Config Mgmt., CI/CD,	YAML, CodeBuild, CodePipeline,
Secrets)	Github Actions, CircleCI, Spacelift,
,	Secrets Manager, Parameter Store,
	Jenkins
Testing Frameworks	Jest, Puppeteer, Artillery, XUnit,
	SpecFlow
Networking	Route53, Cloudflare, Cloudfront,
	VPC, NGINX
Scripting	Python, Bash, Git

Area Ski	lls and Competencies
Project Tracking and Documentation Sen Jira	w Relic, Opsgenie, CloudWatch, atry, Google Analytics a, Confluence, Notion, cidChart, Asana

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics - May 2016, Tennessee State University

Professional Experience

Senior Application Engineer @ HCA

April 2023 - present

- Refactored and reviewed the design of a new internal dashboard written in React.JS. Gave input to management on best practices and how to better adhere to software design principles in development.
- Integrated a new React homepage for employees with third-party services and APIs using their custom built BaaS created by Infor.
- Mentored and assisted junior developers with application development, providing documentation, personal experience and code reviews to help develop growth and reinforce software best practices. Pair programming regularly with developers.

Cloud Platform Engineer II @ Butterfly Network

Dec 2021 - Jan 2023

- Managed a project for architecting a system-wide monitoring and alerting system by integrating AWS Route 53 Health Checks, NewRelic and Opsgenie.
- Managed a project for deploying a brand new mobile POC onto an existing Kubernetes architecture using Helm, Github Actions and Terraform.
- Orchestrated migration of an e-commerce frontend from old AWS architecture to new one using Terraform. Took ownership of configuring and maintaining frontend architecture using Cloudfront.
- Collaborated and led over 20 application deployments to staging and production environments using CircleCI.

- Participated in a Hackathon, leading a team through creating, testing and providing metrics for a load testing framework using Artillery.
- Participated in a 24x7 on-call rotation, successfully supporting brand new Kubernetes architecture.
- Created several Architecture Design documents and presented them to a Design Review committee before implementation.

Junior Software Engineer @ SmileDirectClub

March 2019 - Dec 2021

- Dismantled 3 parts of the company's monolithic e-commerce application into microservices in an agile development environment using scrum and kanban methodologies.
- Implemented microservices using .Net Core and DynamoDb. Deployed services through CI/CD pipeline consisting of Jenkins, Docker, AWS and Terraform.
- Wrote frontend and backend unit and integration tests. Integrated the tests into the CI/CD pipeline.
- Integrated a microservice with RioSEO third party API in order to automate a business need, saving the company at least \$50,000/year in manual data entry. Added components to, maintained and refactored components in company Component Library using Vue.js and Bootstrap.
- Developed MicroUI in Vue.js that integrated with Google Maps API and configured UI to be deployed as a CMS plugin via npm.

Freelance Software Engineer @ Nashville, TN

August 2017 - present

- Designed, implemented, hosted and maintained a media production marketing website using Node.js, Vue.js, AWS and Heroku. Integrated application with Contentful and Airtable.
- Designed, implemented and tested an E-Commerce website developed in .Net Core and JQuery, integrated with Stripe.
- Fully implemented a POC for a custom pre-designed web application in .Net Core with booking and scheduling functionality.

Software Developer Associate @ Accenture

June 2016 - August 2017

• Managed defects, tests, and executed test cases for a monolithic application using Microsoft Test Manager and Microsoft Team Foundation Server.

- \bullet Designed and implemented a solution in C# that records application transactions into the respective database.
- Completed Tricentis Tosca Automation Specialist certification and demonstrated its automation features.